### HANSEL JUNIOR OSPINO ORELLANO



#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Systems engineer and senior Java developer certified in software engineering, nice personal relationships, responsible, flexible, quick learning and leadership skills. Capabilities for programming, designing, developing software and great teamwork aptitudes. Scrum Master certified with experience in software developing over Scrum framework as a development team member. Skills for software developing with Java 8 and 11, REST services, Spring Boot microservices, containerization with Docker, PL/SQL knowledge, Maven, Gradle, JUnit, version control management with GitHub and GitLab, experience with database servers (Oracle, Postgres, SQL Server, MySQL and MongoDB Atlas), issues manager such as JIRA, CI/CD manager as Jenkins and GitLab CI, application servers like Tomcat, IBM Websphere 8.5 and Glassfish 4. Furthermore, I have basic knowledge with AWS Web Services like DynamoDB, Lambda, CloudWatch and SNS. In addition, I have experience developing with open source IDEs such as Intellij IDEA, Eclipse and NetBeans. Basic skills with Javascript, NodeJS, networks and Heroku Cloud Application Platform. Control of operating systems as Windows and Linux.

# PERSONAL INFORMATION

NAME HANSEL JUNIOR OSPINO ORELLANO

**ID NUMBER** 1'140.827.637 from Barranquilla (Colombia)

BIRTHDATE January 11<sup>th</sup>,1990

PLACE OF BIRTH Barranquilla (Colombia)

**ADDRESS** 48th South St # 72 – 50. Apartment 512, El Vergel,

Medellín, Colombia.

**CELLPHONE** +57 3004474106

E-MAIL <u>hjoo0111@gmail.com</u>

LINKEDIN <a href="https://co.linkedin.com/in/hospino11/en">https://co.linkedin.com/in/hospino11/en</a>

# ACADEMIC TRAINING

University education: Systems Engineering

Diplomat of Software Engineering

Simón Bolívar University

2007 - 2012

School: Academic Bachelor

Colegio de Barranquilla "CODEBA"

2001 - 2006

Foreign Language: English – Advanced – Level B2 Upper Intermediate

Speaking (Very Good)

Writing (Advanced)

#### COURSES AND SECONDARY EDUCATION

- Online Course: Java9 New Features Learn by coding it, Tutor Arum Ammasai; duration 6 hours, Udemy; November 2020.
- Online Course: Spring Framework: Spring Data JPA, Tutor Dan Bunker; duration 2.31 hours, Pluralsight; August 2020.
- Online Course: Spring Framework: Spring Boot Actuator, Tutor Dustin Schultz; duration 0.47 hours, Pluralsight; August 2020.
- Online Course: SOLID Software Design Principles in Java, Tutor Dan Geabunea; duration 2 hours, Pluralsight; April 2020.
- Online Course: Spring Framework: Spring Boot Fundamentals, Tutor Kesha Williams; duration 1.38 hours, Pluralsight; April 2020.
- Online Course: Spring Framework: Spring MVC Fundamentals, Tutor Bryan Hansen; duration 2.32 hours, Pluralsight; April 2020.
- Online Course: Spring Framework: Creating Your First Spring Boot Application, Tutor Dan Bunker; duration 1.55 hours, Pluralsight; April 2020.
- Online Course: Spring Framework: Spring Fundamentals, Tutor Bryan Hansen; duration 2.30 hours, Pluralsight; April 2020.
- Online Course: Spring: The Big Picture, Tutor Dustin Schultz; duration 1.15 hours, Pluralsight; April 2020.

- Online Course: Lambda with Functional Programming in Java 8, Tutor Arum Ammasai; duration 10.5 hours, Udemy; February 2020.
- Online Course: Developing on AWS, Tutor Gabriel Ramirez; duration 27 hours, Netec;
  May 28th, 2018 May 30th, 2018.
- Course: Scrum Master, Tutor Angélica Gómez; duration 16 hours, Software Engineering On Time S.A.S. (SEONTI); October 13th, 2015 October 16th, 2015.
- Online Course (MOOC): Agility and Lean. Managing projects and business in XXI century (3rd. edition), Tutor Javier Garzás; duration 50 hours, Miriada X Rey Juan Carlos University; October 12th, 2014 November 5th, 2014.
- Online Course: Quality in software development, Tutor Sebastián Palacio Arango; duration 40 hours, Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje (SENA); February 2nd, 2011 – March 1st, 2011.
- Online Course: Applets/Applications development with databases, networks, Servlets and Multimedia, Tutor Pedro Antonio Martínez Cruz; duration 40 hours, Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje (SENA); July 1st, 2010 – Agosto 1st, 2010.
- Online Course: Applications development with multitask management and menus: Java, Tutor Carmen Emilia Rubio Vanegas; duration, 40 horas, Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje (SENA); May 10th, 2010 June 21st, 2010.
- Online Course: Application development with files and exceptions management in JAVA, Tutor Stiven Betancur Sierra; duration 40 hours, Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje (SENA); March 2nd, 2010 – March 30th, 2010.
- Online Course: Applications development with memory management: Java, Tutor Oscar Javier Oliveros Díaz; duration 40 hours, Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje (SENA); November 20th, 2009 – December 18th, 2009.

- Online Course: Web pages programming with HTML and Javascript, Tutor Rodrigo Borda Caicedo; duration 40 hours, Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje (SENA); August 7th, 2009 – September 9th, 2009.
- Online Course: Database designing in SQL, Tutor Heimar Hernán Coronado Hernández; duration 40 hours, Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje (SENA); July 1st, 2009 – August 3rd, 2009.
- Online Course: Applications development with GUI, Events management, Classes and Objects: Java, Tutor Luis Fernando Ortiz Arroyave; duration 40 hours, Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje (SENA); June 20th, 2009 July 21st, 2009.
- Online Course: Variables and structures in OO programming: Java, Tutor Stiven Betancur Sierra; duration 40 hours, Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje (SENA); February 2nd, 2009 – March 4th, 2009.
- Course: English levels basic, intermediate I, intermediate II, advanced I, advanced II and advanced III; duration 64 hours each level, 384 hours, Language center of Simón Bolívar University, February of 2007 December of 2009.

## **CAREER EXPERIENCE**

**COMPANY:** Globant.

**POSITION:** Java Developer.

FUNCTIONS: Building of Restful services at Disney Cruise Lines with Spring, Java 8

and 11. Building Restful services with Spring Boot at Define DNA Globant project.

BOSS/LEADER: Sebastian Sanabria.

ADDRESS: El Poblado Avenue #5A-113, 16th Floor, One plaza. Medellín - Antioquia

(Colombia).

PHONE: +57 6014891340 extension 44759.

TIME RANGE: Mar 2019 - Current.

**COMPANY:** Bancolombia S.A.

POSITION: Analyst level 2 in the Nequi project.

FUNCTIONS: Implementation of Restful services at Negui project with Java 7. Building

APIs based on NodeJS and AWS services such as Lambda, Dynamo DB and SNS.

BOSS/LEADER: Herbert Gómez Tobón.

ADDRESS: 48th avenue # 20st - 114, 1st floor, Nequi office. Medellín - Antioquia

(Colombia).

PHONE: +57 (4) 4035122.

**TIME RANGE:** Nov 2017 – Mar 2019.

**COMPANY:** Pragma S.A.

**POSITION:** Software Development Engineer.

**FUNCTIONS:** Software development. Focused in the middleware area for the development of a banking system application (known as Nequi of Bancolombia) for

people of different generations, making easy the digital money management.

BOSS/LEADER: Fernando Rengifo.

ADDRESS: Carrera 50 C # 10 Sur - 80. Medellín - Antioquia (Colombia).

**PHONE:** +57 (4) 6052523.

**TIME RANGE:** Jun 2016 – Oct 2017.

**COMPANY:** StackPointer S.A.

**POSITION:** Support and development engineer.

FUNCTIONS: Develop and support of billing software for telecommunications resources

of CW Networks company.

**BOSS/LEADER:** Jorge Miranda.

**ADDRESS:** Carrera 52 # 74 – 56 Office 604 – 605. Barranquilla - Atlántico (Colombia).

**PHONE:** +57 (5) 3587728.

**TIME RANGE:** Jul. 2014 – Jun. 2016.

**COMPANY:** Hypersoft.co S.A.S.

**POSITION:** Development manager

FUNCTIONS: Managing and developing a documental manager system and a workflow

system for customers like Combarranquilla.

**BOSS/LEADER:** Carlos Vega Álvarez

ADDRESS: Carrera 43 # 76 – 184, Office 106. Barranquilla - Atlántico (Colombia).

**PHONE:** +57 (5) 3198482 - +57 3003186856

**TIME RANGE:** Abr. 2013 – Jul. 2014

**COMPANY: DPS S.A.** 

**POSITION:** Development engineer

**FUNCTIONS:** Supporting the implementation of the Atlantis tax system in the town halls of four cities in Atlantico. Verification and correction in the tax system under

JFormsBuilder and JReportsBuilder technologies.

**BOSS/LEADER:** Armando Caro

**ADDRESS:** Carrera 55 # 72 – 73. Barranquilla - Atlántico (Colombia).

PHONE: +57 3126162161

**TIME RANGE:** Dic. 2012 – Feb. 2013

**COMPANY:** ASP Solutions S.A. **POSITION:** Migration engineer

FUNCTIONS: Migration of applications from Oracle Forms and Oracle Reports to Java

technology. Quality assurance of an ERP migrated to Java.

**BOSS/LEADER:** Paola Medina

ADDRESS: Carrara 46 # 70 - 135. Office 14A C.C. Suri II. Barranquilla - Atlántico

(Colombia).

**PHONE**: +57 (5) 3583208

**TIME RANGE:** Feb. 2012 – Ago. 2012

#### REFERENCES

### **PERSONAL REFERENCES:**

NAME Sara Yulieth Henao Rojas

**POSITION** QC Analyst

**PHONE** +57 3182422491

NAME Leidy Yoana Roman Torres

**POSITION** Systems engineer **PHONE** +57 3137173558

**FAMILY REFERENCES:** 

NAME Selideth Paola Ospino Orellano

**PHONE** +57 (5) 3007634480 - +57 (5) 3149630

NAME Paola Andrea Vergara Lopez

**PHONE** +57 3146758175

HANSEL JUNIOR OSPINO ORELLANO

Samonino

ID 1'140.827.637, Barranquilla - Colombia.